# **Steven Boyle - Software Developer**

I love solving problems, working on a team, engaging with stakeholders, and making user friendly apps. I have 6 years of experience building websites using Agile Practices, Test Driven Development, Object Oriented Programming, CI/CD, Cloud-based Services and Microservice Architecture. When I'm not coding I like to cook, make music, paint, and ride my bike.

## **Experience**

#### Club Comic Studio | Software Developer & Consultant | March 2022 - Present

- Developed websites for dozens of satisfied clients.
- Integrated E-commerce, CSV, and PDF capabilities into client's existing code projects.
- Built a customized referral program for a client's web store.
- Assisted clients with Wix, Squarespace, and Shopify websites.
- Consulted clients for best outcomes.

## **EverQuote | Software Engineer | March 2018 - October 2021**

- Designed, tested, deployed, maintained and refactored RESTful API integrations with partners for data transfer and disposition.
- Successfully built data pipelines for 4 new insurance verticals and improved existing verticals.
- Designed reusable components for company wide front end systems.
- Built and launched embeddable and customizable widget for hosting EverQuote services on partner websites.
- Upgraded languages and libraries to keep services up to date.
- Updated and backfilled existing databases.
- Utilized internal, external and cloud based tools for debugging, monitoring and optimizing micro-services.
- Collaborated closely with partners, engineers and enterprise teams to ensure consumer and business satisfaction.
- Trained new engineers and created documentation.

## Launch Academy | Full Stack Software Developer | July 2017 - November 2017

- Developed several Ruby on Rails and React.js applications using test driven development.
- Designed and created an online forum for musicians to receive feedback on their songs.
- Built a user review website for ski slopes and resorts.

#### Education

Launch Academy | Full Stack Software Development Immersive - 2017 University of Massachusetts Boston | B.A. Psychology - 2012 Johnson & Wales University | A.S. Marketing - 2009

#### **Contact**

Email: SKBoyleWork@gmail.com Phone: +1 (781) 724-7310

GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/skboyle">https://github.com/skboyle</a> LinkedIn: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/skboyle0/">https://github.com/skboyle</a>

Portfolio: https://skboyle.github.io/SKBPortfolio